<Document>
  # Server Rules

  # 0. Don't be an asshole
  The rules can't cover every possible situation. Admins should be able to address situations that are missed in the rules.

  Obey the admins. Admins are the authority figures on the server. If they tell you not to do something, you must obey, as the rules cannot cover every situation. However, if you feel that an admin is abusing their authority, you can file a complaint against them.

  Do not try to exploit loopholes in the rules. The most important thing about the rules is their spirit. We are not a world court, but an RP server about playing a 2D stalker game. The rules are made to maintain a pleasant atmosphere and interesting game experience, and to increase engagement. We do not want people who degrade the gaming experience of other players.

  It is forbidden to use nicknames with inappropriate content: directly insulting someone or expressing intolerance towards specific people, groups of people, political or religious spheres. If an administrator asks you to change your nickname, you will have three days to do so, after which you will be banned until you change your nickname. You can change your nickname on the official game website.

  It is also forbidden to intentionally lie to the administration. You will certainly not be banned for inaccuracies in AH, but denying obvious facts will only make things worse.

  Our server has a zero tolerance policy for raiders, which means that you will be permanently banned for raiding, and may also be banned for raiding on other servers.

  If you are clearly against our gaming community and get banned in Discord, you will also be banned from the game.

  # 1. Griefing
  Intentionally spoiling the gameplay of other players.

  The characteristic difference from other offenses in this case is that the offender often does not benefit from it and has no reason behind it, and he does it only to satisfy his desire to fuck things up.

  Also included in this rule are events that have caused significant damage to the gameplay, even though these events were caused without the intent to ruin someone's game. The simplest example is a grenade explosion in a hub location among a crowd of players.

  # 2. Reckless killing (RDM)
  Attacking or physically harming another player for no good reason.
  Reasons for the attack may be as follows:
  Inflicting a serious insult. It should be understood that a quarrel over a bottle is the basis for a fight, but if they move on to relatives in the field - the opponent can be dragged into an anomaly.

  Group Warfare. If you have identified the target as a member of a hostile group, and the war is declared correctly - this is a reason to attack without additional conditions.

  Reflecting an attack. If you are fired upon, you have every right to fight back.

  Intentional harm. If someone tries to push you into an anomaly, calmly discharge everything you have with you into their face.

  Location. Red and black zones and locations are high-risk areas that exclude anyone not penalized by the rules from getting into them. The danger level of locations is described in the rules or set during the event - the current status of the location where the event is taking place can be found in Ahelp.

  Conditionalities are allowed for factions, such as a mercenary contract for a specific person.

  Stalkers, neutral factions are forbidden to specifically hunt their abusers, you are just an ordinary person, not a butcher, yes, you have the right to self-defense, but not for execution. Go to specialized groups to eliminate your abuser (not RPKs).

  # 3. Violation of the game atmosphere
  The action takes place in the Chernobyl exclusion zone with significant deviations in the history of the last 20 years. Your actions and slang should correspond to these realities.

  Using IC chat to communicate on OOC topics (politics, memes, etc.). Using emotion chat to portray various unflattering actions, actions with political overtones. Use of emotion chat for direct communication. Use of paper, PDA messages to publish various drawings with political, erotic and unflattering content. All examples given are in violation of this rule.

  Your character must behave in a manner appropriate to the setting of the game. Running around naked and yelling obscenities is a clear violation of the atmosphere.

  It is impossible to foresee all actions that may spoil the atmosphere of the game. For this reason, you should think twice before committing any extraordinary action.

  # 3.2 Metagame and metacognition
  Use and/or distribution of game information through third-party means of communication, or directly in the game from OOC chat.

  It is forbidden to distribute any meta-information (except for streams) regarding the events currently taking place. After the event is fully completed, it will be known about it in 24 hours from various sources.

  It is allowed to use and somehow play any information known to the player, if you can justify its knowledge, except for information from the current streams. You must learn about any current events either from the information channels of this Discord server, or personally for the character.

  Example: you can know about mutants and events of the original trilogy from the media and the internet, and about the events of the last week in the Zone - from stalkers' tales in hubs.

  Each character has the knowledge, skills and abilities with which he came to the Zone or which he learned already in the Zone. The limit of these skills is determined by the player himself, with the exception of gameplay-implemented limitations.

  For the transfer of IC information in the game there are personal messages and walkie-talkies. Personal messages are used in the PDA, but in the recipient section you must enter instead of “general” nickname from the network of the person to whom you want to transfer information. Or use a walkie-talkie and its frequencies to transmit information in text format.

  You can use Discord to transfer photos, but you must meet in the game and play the transfer of these photos.

  In the game there are hidden factions, especially at the beginning of the vyp, if you have knowledge from the games of the series or books that the man in blue is a mercenary, your character does not know about it, for you it is only a man in blue.

  # 3.3 Death in a raid and RP deaths
  (This rule is not being enforced as most people are brand new and you'll know when it's enforced)
  Death in a raid
  When you die in a raid, you forget everything that has happened to you since the last time you entered the safe zone before you died. This includes forgetting the entire route of your last raid.

  When you die in a raid, it is forbidden to return to the place of death before 15 minutes.

  If you die in a raid, you may not re-enter the battle during which you died, even if the location of the battle has moved.
  RP death and execution
  In the event of a rule violation or if a character is eliminated during an RP execution, the character may be given an RP death.

  Upon RP-death, the player will receive a 24-hour lockout. After RP-death the player:
  1.Must change character.
  2.Cannot join any faction for a week (there may be exceptions).
  3.Loses all accumulated items, RP knowledge and connections.

  After the RP execution must immediately leave the game, any attempts to give anyone items from the treasure trove or money is prohibited.

  Any RP execution must be agreed upon in advance in a special channel. Before requesting permission to execute someone, you should prepare all videos and screenshots that can prove the grounds for execution.

  # 3.4 IC in OOC
  Abuse of OOC and LOOC chats.

  Discussing or mentioning the events of the current round in the OOC channel is forbidden. Messages like “X killed me” or “go get my gear” are especially punishable.

  This also applies to conferences, forums, and other ways of communicating and spreading information. Please note that if you are going to appeal a punishment received during ongoing events, it is better to wait until they are over.

  Outside of the game it is allowed to discuss anything that can be seen from the lobby without entering the game. This includes automatic warnings about various threats, as well as the list of posts.

  The administration can ignore this rule if it's necessary to deal with a certain situation or something similar.

  This rule also applies to LOOCs, but it is allowed to be used for hints in game mechanics.

  # 3.5 Suicide
  Abusing the opportunity to commit suicide or committing suicide without good reason. Intentional withdrawal from playing your role.

  It is forbidden to commit suicide with the help of game mechanics or through commands after you have lost consciousness or been captured. If you have already been lifted from a crit - wagering the captivity to the end.

  It is forbidden to use the ghost and suicide commands for no apparent reason.

  # 3.6 Illiteracy
  Clean speech and observance of grammatical norms of Russian and English.

  It is difficult to talk about any role-playing atmosphere at all, when adult characters, veterans of the Zone, talk like sixth graders at recess.

  Try to make as few mistakes as possible and speak in a language that is pleasant to read without words like “plz”, “sps”, and other “priv”. Naturally, this applies only to healthy characters whose illiterate speech is not reasoned with anything.

  The server languages are Russian and English, Russian-speaking characters are not required to speak English (but is recommended), English-speaking players will not be questioned for any attempts to learn Russian.

  Accent is not a violation and is acceptable if it contributes to the development of RP process, not trolling.

  # 3.7 Maintaining a respectful environment
  Simple human mutual respect between players and each other.

  Excessive/regular insults to other players in OOC chat are prohibited. Repeated gratuitous insults to another player via IC chat may be interpreted as meta-hate.

  As for insults in IC - you need to be moderate. Excessive insults can be detrimental to the RP atmosphere, and it's also obvious that sometimes they are directed at the person on the other side of the screen. Calling someone a “fucking goon” is obviously an insult to a thug character, while insults directed at intelligence or competence are usually directed at the player. Administration may require you to calm down if it crosses the bounds of what is appropriate.

  Harassing someone you don't like OOC during game play through various methods, the list of which includes but is not limited to creating offensive characters, naming animals by that person's nickname/name, mentioning that person IC as part of an offensive reference, giving “special” attention to that person's character IC in order to ruin a round for the person without objective in-game reasons.

  Respect the chain of command when communicating with the Administrator. Insults in the direction of the Administrator can lead to various penalties: from blocking certain chat rooms, to a game ban for extended periods of time. In case the administrator is not right by his actions, instead of insults and clarification of relations, contact the Senior Administrators / write a complaint in the appropriate channel.

  # 4. Character Logic
  Your character, whoever he is: human or mutant, should behave appropriately for his role.

  Take your character creation seriously. The names and surnames of celebrities, actors, characters from movies, TV series, anime, games, etc., as well as similar names and surnames are prohibited. At the same time nicknames can be a reference to mass art or history, nicknames should be put in “quotes”. In this regard, the administration may ask you to change your name, but if you do not change it, you may be subject to action.

  The “Description” tab should only show the external features of your character and nothing else. Therefore, you may not describe your character's fascinating history or personality there!

  Initially, any character must be adequate, unless you are approved for a mentally disturbed character. During the course of events in the Zone, a character may become mentally impaired, but this must be agreed upon with the administration.

  Do not forget what role you are playing. If you play a scientist or military - then the constant swearing and bullish behavior is difficult to call an example of adequate role playing.

  Unfortunately, it is impossible to foresee all situations that fall under this rule. For this reason, it is worth remembering the easiest way to understand whether your actions will clearly violate the logic of the character - think about the purpose of your character does this or that action, whether it has at least a modicum of common sense, and whether the damage that can create this action is justified.

  # 5. Faction Rules
  All factions have their own rules.

  Members of a faction are required to follow their faction's rules, posted in the appropriate channel.

  Factions may have their own lore and their own internal, already in-game rules. Breaking these rules is usually an IC situation, but constantly breaking them can cause questions from the administration.

  All faction rules will be posted in the codex channel of each individual faction.

  # 6. Multi-accounting
  The use of multiple SS14 accounts for gain.

  It is forbidden to create or use more than one account to play on this server.

  Violation of this rule is punishable by a permanent ban.

  # 7. Character
  It is forbidden to change the name and appearance of the character (except hairstyle) without the approval of the administration.

  # 8. Unfair play
  Using software and game flaws to gain an advantage in gameplay.

  In any game, there will always be skillful people who can pull a singularity out of their ass or accelerate themselves to great speeds with the help of an invisible wall. Sometimes it's fun and funny, and sometimes it can crash the server, breaking all the fun of the game. If you find a bug, report it immediately to the appropriate channels on the Discord server.

  It is forbidden to use bugs, cheats, scripts, clickers and other third-party software. INCLUDING IN PVE.

  It is forbidden to copy, save, distribute characters of other players without their knowledge and approval. This also applies to deliberately imitating the name and appearance of other players' characters.

  Intentional creation of a large number of objects on the map, creating a large load on the server, is FORBIDDEN.

  # 9. ERP
  Erotic Role Play.

  Anything more serious than kissing and cuddling is considered ERP. For obvious reasons, it is impossible to anticipate and list every possible variation in the rules, so use common sense. If an administrator orders you to stop anything that is “on the fringe”, you must stop immediately.

  This rule applies to erotic stories that your character may write in books, newsfeeds, on paper, and other in-game media.

  Even if you are the only member of ERP and no one can see you, this does not invalidate the offense.

  The penalty under this rule may not catch up with you right away. If you are not told that you must stop, it does not mean that you are not violating anything, it is just that the administration does not see your violation at the moment, but they will find out later.

  In most cases, violating this rule will result in a permanent ban.

  # 10. Rules for goping and looting
  Everyone, except bandits and renegades (and other factions, if it is described in their rules in the faction rules channel), is forbidden to “gop” and rob neutral players. This means any alienation of another player's property without killing him.

  0.1 In this case, a neutral player means a player you have no reason to kill at the moment.

  0.2. Taking things from characters in the criterion, corpses or characters not controlled by the player (yellow lettering a.k.a. SSD and the like) and attempted pickpocketing outside of Green Zones are allowed for everyone.

  0.3. It is forbidden to rob people in SDD in green zones. This person may have a problem with the game.

  Players have the right to forcibly take away vital supplies if they are refused when asked to share. For example, if there are two more locations left before the safezone, and you have only one magazine left, or if you are bleeding and need a bandage urgently. Only consumables fall under this rule: ammunition, medicines.

  1.1. Abuse of looting for extreme necessity is punishable, if you will often find yourself without supplies in the middle of the Zone - get a penalty for PG.

  Groups are allowed to seize items that are illegal from their point of view and any unique equipment of their faction. The list of such items is set by the administration in the rules of the faction.

  When gop-stop a neutral character (by bandits and similar factions) is allowed to take away a percentage based on the internal hierarchy of gopniki, the higher you are in it, the smaller percentage of gopavy can take away from you. It is recommended to leave enough gear to get to the nearest safe zone. Constant groundless undressing “down to your underwear” can be a reason for a coalition of groups to storm the bandits, perhaps even uniting the state forces with conditional illegals (Neutrals, debt and so on).

  Active resistance (attempts to flee, insults, fighting) during a gop-stop is grounds to put the character in crit and take away his things without regard to paragraph 3. It is still forbidden to kill or leave you for dead, but it is recommended to take you prisoner with a ransom demand, or to set a counter.

  If you are “goped”, you can resist and open fire. In this case, both groups (“gopers” and “goped”) may identify each other as hostile until the end of the fight.

  # 11. Rules for Zones and Bases
  Green Zone
  Green Zones are bars, hub locations, and other publicly accessible areas with traders. These zones are considered absolutely safe due to the protection and authority of traders like Sidorovich who control them.

  • Fleeing into a Green Zone during combat is prohibited. If you’re being pursued, you must first evade your pursuers before entering a Green Zone.

  • Any attacks on players (including detainment and arrests) are prohibited, except for fistfights, even if they are members of a hostile faction.

  • Players in critical condition must be provided assistance.

  • Camping near Green Zones, including the area that fully loads on a client’s screen from the Green Zone’s edge, is prohibited.

  • Green Zone owners or guards are allowed to use force against rule violators within the Green Zone.

  Yellow Zone
  The Yellow Zone is a moderately dangerous area where standard rules apply. These are open locations outside bars and bases. If you’re standing in a field on the Junkyard, chances are it’s a Yellow Zone.
  • All general server rules apply in Yellow Zones. Specifically, RDM (Random Deathmatch) is prohibited.

  Red Zone
  The Red Zone is an area of heightened danger, where survival and every piece of loot are constantly at stake.
  • All initially neutral players may be considered hostile.
  • All initially friendly players may be considered neutral.

  Black Zone
  The Black Zone is an area of extreme danger, where every second could mean catching a grenade from a Monolith member or running into a pseudogiant.
  • All players may be considered hostile, including members of your own faction and allies.
  • Taking players as prisoners is prohibited.

  Southern Checkpoint
  The Southern Checkpoint is a special guarded area. Captured members of the attacking side may be detained and sent to the prison—RPC (Regional Prison Complex).

  Pre-Zone
  Certain areas are designated as Green Zones (GZ) within the Pre-Zone, where all conflicts and camping are prohibited. These include the supermarket, Trader's section, faction stash building, and the shared stash. Except for the supermarket, these zones are also off-limits for patrols and searches by government forces.

  The Research Institute and the police station are designated as government force Green Zones.

  The Journalist Headquarters is their Green Zone.

  Government forces are authorized to capture from Crit or RPC anyone who attacks law enforcement representatives within controlled areas of the Pre-Zone.

  Wearing patches of illegal factions within the Pre-Zone is grounds for a search and detainment by government forces for identity verification.

  Location Zones:
  Black Zones: None

  Red Zones:
  "Oasis" (Sin faction location)
  Red Forest

  # -----------------The following rules regulate special aspects-----------------
  # 12. Rules for Raiding Faction Bases and Green Zones
  • An attack on a Green Zone or a faction base requires prior approval from the game administration, with a rank no lower than Game Master. Authorized administrative members have the right to delegate the task.

  • The conditions for the raid are agreed upon individually and are not immediate. The date of the raid is also agreed upon separately.

  • During a raid, any stalkers or factions may participate, as long as it is agreed upon with the raid organizer.

  • The maximum number of participants, their equipment, the status of the nearest location(s), victory conditions, and other aspects are determined individually by the responsible administrative member.
  RP Execution Rules
  • RP execution must be requested in advance in the designated channel.
  • If the RP execution rules are violated, it may be counted as an additional punishment for the player at the discretion of the administrator handling the situation.
  • During an RP execution, returning to the previous faction within a month is prohibited. This is cumulative with previous bans from the RPC.

  Leaving to a Personal Stash During an RP Situation

  • Violations of this rule are treated as violations of rule 8 for players.

  • Fleeing from someone or going to a stash during RP to escape pursuit is strictly prohibited, as is any attempt to avoid pursuit or steal items. Once you have hidden from pursuit and a minute has passed, this rule no longer applies.

  # Identification Rules (Temporary, until mechanics are implemented)
  • Violations of this list are treated as violations of rule 4.

  • A character can only be recognized by voice if you are very familiar with them or if you have a voice recording (video of a conversation with the character).

  • A character can only be recognized by facial features if their face is not obscured and you have a photo or description of the person. The demand to "show your face" in most situations will be considered metagaming. Think twice about whether you have grounds to ask for someone to "show their face."

  • In combat, all unidentified individuals may be considered enemies.

  • Anyone moving in the same group as a person identified as an enemy may be considered an opponent.

  # Identifying a Character as an Enemy
  Once a character is identified as an enemy, you may open fire first without additional conditions.

  • Violating this list is treated as a violation of rule 2.
  • In the Pre-Zone: Everyone is considered neutral, regardless of faction patch or diplomatic status.
  • By Patch: If a character wears a patch of a hostile faction, they are considered an enemy.

  • Without a Patch: If a character has no patch, they may be considered an enemy.

  • If there is a mechanic for changing patches, attacking enemies of your faction while disguised, or using disguise for surprise attacks, is prohibited unless absolutely necessary.

  • Awareness of a player's faction, who is wearing a hidden patch, obliges you to identify them according to their faction.

  # Abusing Economic Defects and Interfering with the Economy
  • Violating this rule is treated as a violation of rule 8 for players.

  • Using server bugs or defects to gain equipment, money, or loot will result in a wipe of your stash and gear unless you immediately report the issue to the administration.

  • Gaining an unfair advantage through administrative assistance (point 3 of admin violations) may result in a wipe of your stash and gear, RP death, and in some cases, a ban if collusion is proven.

  • Discovering bugs and errors may reward you with an in-game prize if you have not used them previously for personal gain.

  • Government factions are prohibited from abusing supply and leaking it into the economy.

  • It is prohibited to "leak" faction common supplies for everyone (when deserting, the amount you can steal with you is discussed with the curator).

</Document>
