<Document>

# Welcome to S.T.A.L.K.E.R. SS14!

<Box>Don't forget to follow the rules.[/bold] They can be found here:</Box>
<Box>[color=blue]https://discord.gg/pu6DEPGjsN[/color]</Box>
You can ask a question or write about a violation of the rules to [color=#EB2D3A][bold]administration[/bold][/color] using [bold]AHelp[/bold]. ([italic] opens when you press [/italic][color=yellow][bold][keybind="OpenAHelp"/][/bold][/color])

Ты всегда можешь открыть эту страницу снова, используя [color=yellow][bold][keybind="OpenGuidebook"][/bold][/color].

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="gbs_info" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]About the server[/bold]:
S.T.A.L.K.E.R. SS14. - Server with [italic]meta-progression[/italic] and elements of an [italic]MMO[/italic]. This implies the preservation of the character for the entire duration of the wipe, the constant development of the preserved IC relationships, [italic]preservation[/italic] of equipment and money between rounds in personal stashes, equipment divided into conditional levels. Our server provides the opportunity for free development and roleplaying of your character, as well as various activities and mechanics.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHumanDummy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]Character Creation[/bold]:
When creating a character - be careful and attentive, since the server does not have the ability to change the character after creation (however, if necessary, you can ask AHelp for help with saving).

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandLogo" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]First steps[/bold]:
The first place you appear on the server is Purgatory. The initial spawn hub, from where you and the rest of the players will have to choose your spawn location. The most beginner-friendly option is the village. This is a safe area with a merchant, a personal stash, and a fire. If you go down to the basement of the village, you can find a descent to the stash (called the Lair), in which your belongings are stored. Click on the blue machine to open the stash interface. At the start, everyone has a starting capital of [color=yellow] 2 thousand rubles[/color]. When you click the "take" button, don't forget to pick up your money as it appears next to the storage machine. After taking it, find the basement of Sidorovich, the local NPC trader. There you can buy basic equipment.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Roubles" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]Earning your first roubles[/bold]:
  Got some basic gear? The easiest activity for a beginner is hunting. After killing a game, you can almost always skin the carcass, getting valuable trophies that are bought by traders. In this simple way, you can make your first fortune. Don't forget about the safety cushion!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterBloodyPrint" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]Death[/bold]:
Died? Anything can happen in the Zone. After your death, you will find yourself in the lobby, where you can respawn. However, remember, the rules forbid returning to the place of death or to battle!
Dying in a raid doesn't force you to change your character, but you can only permanently lose your character if they are "executed", which other people need a good reason for.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterBilly" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

[bold]What's next[/bold]?
After you become accustomed to such a lifestyle, you will probably have a question - what to do next? Where is "insert the necessary"? It's pretty simple - [color=yellow][bold]Communication[/bold][/color]!
Don't be afraid to look for teachers among seasoned stalkers, cooperate with other beginners for the sake of a joint hunt, or ask questions around the campfire.
There is a huge amount of information and benefits that you can get through simple communication.

[bullet] Artifacts and anomalies.
      [bullet] Anomalies from the original and more.
      [bullet] Equipment for searching for artifacts and protecting against anomalies
      [bullet] Artifacts with their properties and places of appearance.
      [bullet] Clusters of anomalies - Archanomalies

# Minor Mechanics and Changes

[bullet] Berries can be harvested from the bushes, which can be used as food or to create medicines.

[bullet] A special weight system that affects movement speed and the anomalies that interact with it.

[bullet] Treatment in sleep on beds is accelerated several times

[bullet] Stamina consumption and acceleration while running.

# Hotkeys

[bullet] You can lie down with F.

[bullet] You can run by holding down the Shift key.

[bullet] In the settings, you can assign a key to quickly interact with the armor storage, similar to the backpack and belt (Their use is highly recommended).

This is basic knowledge that can be useful for beginners. Explore the exclusion zone and chat with other players to learn more!

</Document>
