<Document>
  # Core Rule 11 - Faction Rules and Information

  Factions at war are allowed to shoot each other on sight outside of [color=#008000]Green Zones[/color]. Some factions are locked in perpetual war and will never be changed, same applies for some alliances. Other wars and alliances are determined by the faction leaders.

  Faction members should not hand out exclusive faction gear willy nilly without permission from the faction lead. This is especially true for factions that spawn with free kits like the Military and Monolith. Faction members should also not be letting non-faction members see/use their shops without permission from their leader.

  When traveling in a group, if a member of your group is of a different faction and is being shot at by a member of one of their rival factions, you are allowed to assist
  your group member if you wish.

  Members of a faction should always be playing as that faction. You should not pick Loner if you are in a faction.

  Factions are required to role-play as the faction they are playing. The leader must ensure if they recruit members the person joining has AT LEAST a basic understanding of the faction's lore and playstyle. This is to maintain an interactive experience.

  Faction leaders are held to a higher standard of role-play and should maintain their factions rules and check on their subordinates.

  If your faction is not listed here, then you have no specific faction rules or perpetual wars/alliances and should follow your leader's rules. You should also follow your leader's rules even if you have rules here too. Leader rules should not overwrite faction rules.

  Note: All factions are at war with Monolith.

  * Information on faction tabs is not for in-character knowledge, this is OOC knowledge for a better understanding of expected gameplay.*

  - [textlink="Bandits" link="RuleF1"]

  - [textlink="Renegades" link="RuleF2"]

  - [textlink="Military" link="RuleF3"]

  - [textlink="Monolith" link="RuleF4"]

  - [textlink="Ecologist" link="RuleF6"]

  - [textlink="Mercenaries" link="RuleF7"]

  - [textlink="Duty" link="RuleF8"]

  - [textlink="Freedom" link="RuleF9"]

  - [textlink="Clear Sky" link="RuleF10"]
</Document>
