<Document>
  # Core Rule 8 - Do not RDM and Zone Rulings

  In most scenarios, you should not be shooting/attacking people as soon as you see them. However, there are zones where player versus player (PVP) is allowed. Robbing and looting should also not be your first go in general situations.

  PVP should not be done near transitions (Portals) to other regions. You should remain around at least .5 to 1 screen away from transitions to maintain fair playstyle. It can be hard to judge as some transitions are in tighter areas, so it’s better to err on the side of caution. You may only PvP in these areas such as; someone has fled to the transition or has been sitting there for over 30 seconds.

  You should be at least three screens away from a green zone to initiate PVP or robbing. *Camping a transition or green zone will be punished severely.*

  [color=#008000]Green Zones:[/color] PVP is strictly prohibited in these areas. These areas serve as safe hubs for trading and are often visited by new or inexperienced players. No form of player combat is allowed within these zones. *IMPORTANT* Bandits, Renegades, Monolith are not allowed to enter Rookie Village.

  Locations:
  - Rookie Village in Cordon including Sidorovich's bunker.
  - The 100 Rads Bar in Rostok. (Duty controls Rostok. Any hostile or associates to said factions may be denied entry or even engaged on sight within Rostok or the Bar. Enter at your own Risk.)
  - Faction bases. (Unless Admin approved for a raid)

  [color=#808080]Gray Zone:[/color] PvP and Robbing is allowed only after there is an RP exchange in the encounter if allowed depending on faction rules and faction relations.

  Locations:
  - Cordon (Except Southern Boarder, Military can open fire)

  [color=	#4169E1]Faction Bases:[/color] Faction base owners have the final say. They may use lethal force if the offender is violating their rules when appropriate or escalated. You may also have to comply with reasonable requests, ie: while in government facilities, you may be detained or lose access to the facility for breaking the law.

  * Attacking faction bases without raid approval is prohibited.

  * Camping a faction base or the only access points to it is prohibited. Any faction that is hostile to base owning faction must remain .5 screens away.

  * Ignoring or resisting orders from faction members while in their base is prohibited.


  [color=#FFFF00]Yellow Zones:[/color] PVP and robbing allowed depending on faction rules and faction relations. Factions at war are allowed to PVP on sight in a yellow zone.

  Locations:
  - Anything not specified in the other zones.

  [color=#FF0000]Red Zones:[/color] On sight PVP is allowed with neutral or hostile factions. Same faction members and allies of your faction should not be shot at.

  Locations:
  - Red Forest
  - Capture Points

  [color=#000000]Black Zones:[/color] On sight PVP is allowed regardless of faction alignment. Same faction members should not be shot at.

  Locations:
  - Limansk
</Document>
